# Luis Herrera

Cali, Valle del Cauca 1209@holbertonschool.com 3057128788

Cryptocurrency privacy-focused Monero (XMR) enthusiast. Focused in open-source software GNU/Linux operating systems since 2016.

Studied Software Engineering foundations at Holberton School Colombia with a high passion for blockchain technology.

Entrepreneur, adventurer, and eager to develop code for our world.

Experience in C, Python, and JavaScript programming languages, hand-coded HTML and CSS with MySQL database integration.

## Work Experience

### **Communication Work-group Coordinator (Volunteer)**

Monero

July 2018 to Present

Workgroup production coordinator. Organize translators, transcriptionist's workload and publish final content throughout the community.

## **Software Engineer**

Rappi - Cali

May 2020 to June 2020

This project proposes a workforce based credit system, implementing technology and performance. The main goal is to facilitate fast loan access to workers based on their performance. We have two main participants.

Investors and workers. Investors invest in the loan system based on the worker's score and workers will have access to the loan depending on their performance.

### **Software Engineer**

Holberton School - Cali

September 2019 to June 2020

Full-time programmer. Experience with C, Python, and Javascript programming languages, MySQL (SQLalchemy) database management, HTML, and CSS web frameworks.

During this project, we developed 3 low-level C programming & algorithms projects, 4 higher level Python and JavaScript programming projects, 8 system engineering DevOps projects, a Social Media profile, and our own portfolio project that was live transmitted through Facebook live. We also used MySQL as relational database management systems, SQLalchemy, RESTful, and JavaScript APIs and deployed virtual servers using Docker and hardware servers.

#### **Database Analyst**

EMCALI - Cali

September 2016 to February 2018

Database analyst. I also did the Geographic Information System software (GEOVISOR/MapInfo) colleagues training. My main task was to maintain the database information updated using the integrated OPEN-SmartFlex software. Databases were handled using Microsoft Excel crossed-based between different government official databases (FOSYGA, RUAF, DIAN, and PROCURADURIA).

### **Business Development Administrator**

Productos Vrinda February 2013 to May 2016

Production and service manager. My responsibilities were to cover the customer service area, staff planning, purchase, storage, and sales. I had to contact suppliers, make the financial accounting control, have resource optimization, and comply with quality standards and regulations of the food and beverage sector.

Georeferencer

#### Georeferencer

Servinformación - Cali February 2010 to February 2013

Feb 2010 - Feb 2013 (3 years 1 month)

Homologue national property number in the company's databases to the EMCALI subscriber. I also made routing fieldwork through Geographic Information Systems (GIS). Geographic software layer control, collector supervisor, and location coordinates updates. Software: MapInfo, Excel, Access.

### **Commercial Director**

Chef en Tu Casa - Cali January 2012 to May 2012

Logistics, purchases, accounting, and cash management.

#### **CSR**

Kimeline

December 2010 to March 2011

Customer Service Representative

### Education

## **School in Software Engineering**

Holberton School - Cali September 2019 to September 2021

### **Certificate in Web Development**

Udemy Academy - Cali September 2017 to March 2018

#### **Bachelor's in Economics**

Universidad Libre de Occidente - Cali September 2006 to September 2011

## Skills

- English
- Open-Source Software
- Programming
- Software Development
- Business Strategy
- Project Management
- MySQL
- Microsoft Office
- Microsoft
- JavaScript
- CSS
- HTML5
- APIs
- C/C++
- Git
- REST

### Links

http://linkedin.com/in/lh1008

https://github.com/lh1008

## Certifications and Licenses

# EF SET English Certificate 94/100 (C1 Advanced)

July 2020 to Present

https://www.efset.org/cert/4TKkn8